

BRAHIM SLITI DEVOPS ENGINEER

brahim.sliti15@gmail.com G Permit, French nationality Born June 13, 1998 github.com/SlitiBrahim linkedin.com/in/brahim-sliti/ Driving license, with a car

Innovative DevOps Engineer with a problem-solving mindset and experiences in software engineering. As a DevOps Engineer at Wanadev, built a CI/CD pipeline to deploy video games patches in 50 arcade rooms in Europe and reduced release time by 30%. At the HUG, wrote Python scripts which increased the speed of the data acquisition process by 80%.

SKILLS

Software Engineering

- Cut out an application into micro-services and reduced the risk of failure of this databases synchronization system by 40%.
- Developed applications and APIs with Python. Wrote scripts to gather HUG patients data which took the data acquisition process up to 80% faster.

DevOps

- Managed continuous integration / continuous delivery of 15 video games to 50 arcade rooms and increased release time by 30%.
- Built a CI/CD pipeline which boosted the training time of a Machine Learning model to 70%.
- Used Kubernetes to deploy personal projects and Ansible to configure my AWS servers.

EXPERIENCE



DEVOPS CONSULTANT INTERN



Qim Info / HUG | Geneva, January 2020 - July 2020 Reference: Ousmane BA, Head of Data Lab, ousmane.ba@qiminfo.ch

- Technical leader within a team of 4 Data Scientists.
- As a DevOps engineer in a Data Science team, built a CI/CD pipeline to train a Machine Learning model and reduced the training time by 70%.
- Developed a powerful Python program that increased data acquisition time by 80%.
- Introduced the use of development best practices, allowing to increase the team development time by 30%.



STUDENT PART-TIME DEVOPS ENGINEER

Wanadev | Lyon, July 2018 - November 2019

Reference: Manuel KLEIN, CTO, mklein@wanadev.fr

- Restructured a database synchronization Golang service into micro-services communicating through RabbitMQ queues:
 - Reduced the risk failure of this business-critical application by 40%.
 - Allowed to increase the speed of debugging and features development by 2.
- As a DevOps Engineer in a new team of 6 game developers, set up a CI/CD pipeline to better integrate new code and deploy game patches for 15 games in 50 game rooms in Europe:
 - Optimized release time by 30%.
 - Reduced development and testing time by 15%.



FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

Prefecture of Rhône | Lyon, August 2017 - September 2017 Reference: Jean Noël PONNELLE, CTO, jn.ponnelle@blue-tools.net

- Designed a MySQL Database to load +100 institutions data.
- Developed a public PHP Web application which allowed to search for institutions that support persons with reduced mobility.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Developed a Python app that enables to spawn a fresh video website listing specific subject videos from different sources.
- Created a cryptocurrency with Python inspired by the Bitcoin technology.
- Currently training to pass the Kubernetes CKAD certification.

EDUCATION

MASTER DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

SUPINFO INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY | Lyon, Octobre 2016 - July 2019 Reference: Nadège Aumont, SUPINFO Headmistress, contact: bit.ly/3j214zO

- Excelled in programming classes.
- Officially certified for Security of web applications, services and servers.
- Passion for DevOps and management courses that gave me the DevOps philosophy I have.

HOBBIES

- Participant of DevOps meetups in Geneva to stay up to date with the latest technologies.
- Amateur footballer to achieve goals and aim for performance as a team.
- Reading personal development books to sharpen my soft skills, boost my motivation and always reach my objectives.

LANGUAGES

- French: native speaker.
- English: B2.